Guide to the Abraham Yates, Jr. papers, 1604-1825 [bulk 1760-1796]
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- CHRONOLOGICAL LIST
  - 74. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yats Junr. Refers to Yates desire to be appointed Sheriff-on the death of the person then holding the office. A. L, S. 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, 1761 May 11
  - 75. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Mr. James Stevenson, Merchant In Albany. "I have ordered my young man to go up with the pitts-jagos & to Carry as much bar Iron for you as It will conveniently load". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Ma, 1761 July 9
  - 76. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. in Albany, Refers to Mr, Stevenson & some business with the Sheriff. "As head Quarters Is now in your City, doubtless you have all the news Running, as I here am barren must Entreat you to Com, 1761 July 21
  - 77. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany. "I was in great hopes that after the Reduction of all Canada arbitrary power and all other Illegal proceedings by the Gentlemen of the army would have been at an End. You tell me a, 1761 July 28
  - 71. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. att Albany. Refers to the disposition of the troops then stationed on Staten Island; to the War on the Continent; mentions Cell. Grant, Sir William Johnson & Gen, Monckton, "I have not heard t, 1761 August 5
  - 79. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, att Albany. Wishes Hendrick Bogart to come down to put a new bottom in his Sloop. "The fleet is Saild I hear for Barbados their to make the randevous for gethering the whole fleet & army toge, 1761 December 2
  - 80. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. An Interesting letter relating to affairs in Germany, Spain, Denmark, Russia &.; also commenting on domestic news. "By the Speech of his Honr. to the Assembl, 1761 December 8
  - 81. Wendell, Harmanus H.; addressed to his father, Harmanus Wendell, Merchant in Albany, "Mr. John Fry tells me he has Been Drunk For Six Weeks upon a Stretch and is So Every Day". Autograph letter signed, 1 p, folio, dated Schenectady, 1762 January 16
  - 82. Wendell, Harmanus. Memorial addressed by Harmanus Wendell, Lucas Van Veghten & another to Sir Jeffery Amherst, Commander in Chief of all his Majesties forces In America, requesting a Pass to go from Albany to Montreal. Draft of Document in autograph o, 1762 January 23
  - 83. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. Referring to a "white Seader Swamp" & enclosing a letter of Yates, relating to Yan Bergen's land. A, L. S, 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, 1762 February 8
  - 84. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. Referring to the unpleasant feeling existing between the late & present Mayors, & mentioning the sale of lots In the Saratoga Patent. Autograph letter signed, 1762 March 4
  - 85. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., attorney at Law In Albany. Mentions Killeen De Ridder, Mr Lydius, Mr. Stevenson & Mr. Silvester. "A Spanish War seems to threaten & perhaps we are on the Eve of it. It's true we are at, 1762 March 13
  - 86. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. Refers to the request of the English "Prisbaterians" for a meeting-house, where the "Grenery" now stands. "I Congratulate you on the Reduction of Martinico, 1762 April 19
  - 87. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Attorney at Law In Albany. "I want to hear how our army at Martinico is to be disposed of for the Summer Season and what other Expeditions we are to undertake". Autograph letter signed, 1762 May 8
  - 88. Duncan, John, addressed to Mr. William Corry Esq. in Albany. Refers, to the costs of some suit. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady, 1762 August 17
  - 89. Livingston, Robert, Junr., addressed to Abraham, Yates Junr. Esqr. att Albany. Referring to trouble in the church & mentioning the birth of a child in Yates' family. "I am just going to a bon Fire I have Caused to be Erected as a testimony of our Joy, 1762 September 13
  - 90. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph to Robert Livingston. Refers to the division of a Patent "that join on the Half Moon". "Antony Van Schayck Brake the chain, after some Discourse about the Consequences of Shopping the Commissione, 1762 September 27
  - 91. Livingston, Robert, Junr., to Abraham Yates Junr. Referring to Coll. Van Rensselaer's meeting with his tenants and the validity of their leases, Also mentions Mr. Jeremiah Van Rensselaer. Autograph letter signed, 1 p. folio, dated Manor Livingston, 1762 December 2
  - 92. Corry, William, addressed to Mr, Joseph Howard, Merct. In Montreal. Enclosing a bond of Hans Legars due to Alexander McKay. "The news., at present is the peace by which Canada is [doubt-] to the; English. Autograph letter signed 1 p, folio, dated Alba, 1763 March 11
  - 93. Williston, John, addressed to Mr. Wm. Yates att Albany Atorney att. Law. Asking advice as to how he should proceed in his action with Parsons. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated Springfield, 1764 July 18
  - 94. Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, addressed to Robert Yates Esqr., Attorney at Law, Albany. Asking him to arrest immediately one Jacob of Cloverack. "John Mc Combes has Settled with me Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York, 1764 September 9
  - 95. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Samuel Dunham. Draft of letter in his autograph. Relative to his suit with Thoma Smith Junr. of Charles Town, South Carolina, 1 p. quarto, 1764 September 13
  - 96. Van Rensselaer, Stephen. Receipt given by him to Abraham Yates Junr. D. S. 1 p. folio, in autograph of Peter W. Yates and also signed by him, 1764 September 17
  - 97. Winne, Jellis. His bill against Abm. Yates Junr., the same being receipted July 10, 1765. A. D. S, in Dutch, 1 p, small quarto, 1765 January
  - 98. McKay, Alexander. His bill against Jno. McFall for the amount of which he brings suit. D. S, 1 p, folio, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yatts Esqr. Attorney at Law in Albany, 1765 February 7
  - 99. Ten Eyck, Jacob C. (Judge), Affidavit of Christian Ehl In his case against Thomas Winn. D. S. 1 p. folio, 1765 May 25
  - 100. Yates, Abraham, Junr. His affidavit relative to the head of a wolf brought before him by Michael Lantman. A. D. S. 1 small square, 1766 November 4
  - 102. Yates, Robert. Copy of Complaint of Thomas Winn, through Robert Yates his attorney, against Christian Aile, for selling him a bay stallion under false pretences & asking damages to the extent of eighteen pounds. D. 2 p. folio, 1767 January
  - 103. Silvester, Peter. Bill of costs In suit of Janneke Van Hoosen against Dirck Van Derheyden, receipted by Silvester as Attorney for Defendant. D. S. 1 p. quarto, 1767 May 19
  - 103. Wendell, Evert. Draft of Indenture (part of it in the autograph of Abm. Yates Junr.) between Evert Wendell & Hendrick Wendell of Sinckhaick, of the one part, and John Johannis Fonda, son of Susanna, one of the daughters of Abm. Wendell doc'd, of the, 1767 June
  - 104. De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to sell the "chattels, lands & Tenements of James Howells" to satisfy his debt to John Magee. Indorsed on the back by Har. Schuyler, sheriff. D. S. oblong strip, 1767 June 5
  - 105. Yates, Peter. Indenture & Copy of Mortgage Bond of house and lot in the second ward of the city of Albany. D. S. by Peter Yates, Johannis Saml. Pruyn, Matthew Visscher, Christopher P. Yates & others. 5 p. folio, 1767 November 16
  - 106. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter to Alexander McKay. Relative to his various legal suits. 2 p. quarto, dated, Albany, 1768 February 8
  - 107. Taylor, William, addressed to Mr. [DOUBT-] La Grange Living at the Hellebargh. Mentioning his father's will & advising him to subject Ary La Grange to a strict cross-questioning regarding the same. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Hellebargh, 1769 March 23
  - 108. Rogers, John, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates, Attorney at Law in Albany, Asking information regarding some case at law. A, L. S, 1 p, folio, dated New York, 1768 September 24
  - 109. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Mr, Hyde, some of Capt. Hide at Sarachtoge, Behind Walran Clute. Requesting him to some down, get his Lease & pay the Debt which his father owed, L, S. 1 p. quarto, dated Albany, 1769 April 11
  - 110. Wendell, Harmanus, Draft of his Will, part of it in the writing of Abraham Yates Junr. D, 4 p. folio, 1769 May 25
  - 111. Winne, Anthony, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates at Albany. Requesting him to collect from Peter Bronck the money he was owing Winne for a load of hay. Autograph letter signed 1 p. small quarto, dated Cosakkey, 1769 September 5
  - 112. Van Schaick, Wessel, Two Bills of Exchange drawn on Mesers, Sargent Chambers & Co., Merchants in London, in favor of Wessel Van Schaick & signed by Reade & Yates, D, 1 p, quarto, dated New York, 1770 August 24
  - 113. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Saml., Jones Esqr. In behalf of Corporation. Requesting his opinion in a case. Autograph letter draft, 1771 February 3
  - 114. Yates, Abraham, Junr., Relating to the first settlement of Albany, "I now propose to add the reasons that induces me to think that the West India Company by Virtue of their Grant from the States of Holland had no right to the Possessions, Commons & o, 1771 March 19
  - 115. Ten Eyck, Henry, Junr. His receipt for 42 pounds 6 shillings. D. S. 2 p, quarto, 1771 May 14
  - 116. Banyar, George, to the Hon. Robert R. Livingston & George Duncan Ludlow, Esquires. "Some Time after the last River- Circuit I was informed that the Mayor and Magistrates of the City of Albany had, in an Address transmitted to the Lieutenant Governor, 1771 June 5
  - 117. Jones, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr Esqr. in Albany. "It seems the first Settlers of Albany either conquered or purchased the Lands of the Indians. I suppose they settled as Subjects and under the Protection of the States General in which, 1771 July 12
  - 118. De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring one Benjamin Springer before the next Inferior Court of Common Please. A. D. S. oblong strip, 1772 January 24
  - 119. Yates, Abraham. Complaint made by John Mahoney, through Abraham Yates, his attorney, against Benjamin Springer for failure pay him various sums of money borrowed from said Mohawney. D. 3 p. folio, 1772 June
  - 120. De Lancey, Stephen (Clerk). Order Issued to the Sheriff of Albany County to bring John Mohany before the next Inferior Court of Common Pleas. D. S. oblong strip, 1772 June 5
  - 121. Douw, Volckert P, (Judge). Referring to Benjamin Springer's delivery to Bail. D. S. 1 p. quarto, 1772 September 22
  - 122. Mohawney, John. An order to pay to Cornelius Glen the amount due him. Signed by Matthew Visscher, Abraham Yates Junr. & Cornelius Glen. D. signed by Mohawney's mark, 1 p, folio, dated Albany, 1772 September 30
  - 123. Winn, John, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, Asking him to call on his as soon as possible to give his advice regarding action toward his creditors. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany City Hall, 1773 May [DOUBT-]
  - 124. Schuyler, Philip; Ten Broeck, Abraham; Livingston, Peter R.; addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. Chairman of the Committee of Correspondence, Albany. Interesting letter relative to important decisions of the House of Assembly. "You will at one glance per, 1774 February 25
  - 125. Yates, Richard. Order on Messrs Sargent Chambers &Co, of London to pay one hundred pounds to Evert Bancker or. Endorsed by Evert Bancker. A, D. S. oblong strip, dated New York, 1774 March 23
  - 126. Yates, Abraham, Junr Drafts of a letter A resolutions passed at a meating of the committee of Correspondence of the City & County of Albany. Refers principally to the needs of the inhabitants of Boston. & the determination of the citizens of Albany t, 1774 December 10
  - 127. Low, Isaac (Chairman), to Mr, Jacob Lansing, Chairman of the committee of the City and County of Albany. Relating to some goods for warded to Mr, Abraham Schuyler & Mr. Andrew McFarlin. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York, 1774 December 15
  - 128. Six Nations. Document, 3 p. quarto, part in autograph of Abn. Yates Junr. Endorsed: - "Answer of the Six Nations to the Speech of the 12 United Colonies 1775"
    Also, Document, 1 p. quarto, endorsed "Speech to the Indians when they recd the Presents".
  - 129. Bleecker, Henry. to John N. Bleecker & Rutger Bleecker, Committee. Stating two questions on which it is requested "that the Inhabitants of this ward Signify their assent or Dissent", D S. 1 p. folio, dated Albany, Also signed by Jacob Bleecker" Jacob, 1775 March 21
  - 130. Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman of the Committee, Albany. Introducing Col. Flemming, "A gentleman appointed by this Congress adjutant General to the Army under the [doubt-] of General Schuyler". Autograph letter signed, 1775 September 6
  - 131. Brewster, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. "As the only members of the Committee of Safety now present we forward this to you & pray you to make the best use of the Intelligence & your Time". L. S. 1 p. folio, dated New Yor A, 1776 January 2
  - 132. Gansevoort, Leonard, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, Chairman of the Committee of the City and County of Albany. Transmitting parcells of pamphlets. "The Congress met yesterday morning and preceeded to business. The Ships of War in this Harbou, 1776 February 13
  - |33. Benson, Robert (Secretary). A copy of Resolves of Congress to give Money on Loan to the Counties mentioned. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated In Provincial Congress, New York, 1776 March 13
  - 134. McKerlie, John. His affidavit concerning Ensign Howard, "The people seem to be suspicious of General Schuyler and his proceedings and that they were also suspicion that the Provisions going were for the use of the King's Troops". D. S. 1 p. folio, 1776 May 18
  - 135. Jansen, Dirck, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Chairman off the Committee at Albany. Asking for six Gentlemen to come down to assist the Militis of Dutchese County of their movement against the disaffected people in his District D. S, 1 pf fo, 1776 May 19
  - 136. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Abraham Yates Esq, and in. his absence to Matthew Visscher Esq, in Albany. Interesting letter asking assistance from the Albany Committee. "We have just reed. Intelligence by Express from Oneida that a large Body o, 1776 June 8
  - 137. Yates, Abraham, Junr, Draft of letter in hia autograph, endorsed- "to Rt. Yates". Concerning the sale of some wine, Small square piece, dated Albany, 1776 June 10
  - 138. Gansevoort, Leonard. Interesting Document also signed by Philip Livingston (the Signer), Thos. Randall, Gouv. Morris, Thomas Fred- well & Lewis Graham Summon to Wb. Backers of Westchester Co., Issued by a Committee of the Congress of the Colony of Ne, 1776 June 27
  - 139. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to the Committee of Albany, Also signed by Mat. Adgate A Jno. J. Bleeckar. "Yesterday a Committee was appointed to draw up & Resolve to Put you under a Peremptory Rule to furnish the Congress with your Proceedings aga, 1776 July 26
  - 140. Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. An intersting letter, narrating the experiences of Maj. Bigelow, who was sent with a flag from our Array to the Commander of the British Troops. A, L. S. 3 p. folio, dated Albany, 1776 August 19
  - 141. Yates, Robert. Interesting document giving extracts from the Resolves of the Committee of Safety for the State of New York, In reference to the purchase of wheat for the use of the Continental Army and the execution of certain coopers from militia du, 1776 October 29
  - 142. Wisscher, Matthew, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Kingston. Interesting letter referring to the condition of Schoharie, mentioning Gen. Arnold as "gone to the westward", & repeating Col. Willett's interesting description of affaire at Fort S, 1777 August 15
  - 143. Congress, Committee of. Copies of letters sent to His Excellency George Clinton, Govr, of the State of New York. Also several copies of letters of Gen. Washington. "We again entreat you in the most earnest, in the most urgent Manner, to use every Exe, 1780 May 25-June 23
  - 144. Clinton, George (Gov.), copy of his letter to Congress. Explaining the inability of New York State to comply with the requisitions of Congress. 16 p. folio., dated Albany, 1781 February 5
  - 145. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Henry Glen Esq., A. D, Q. M. Genl. Schenectady, Declining to accept a sent in either House of the Legislature, for family reasons. "As to major Frey I know his Sentiments on the Subject so well that I am well convi, 1781 April 7
  - 146. Morris, Robert, to his Excellency, The Governor & Commander in Chief of the State of New York. Concerning the account of the United States against the State of New York. "Your Excellency must be sensible of the Impracticability of carrying on the War, 1781 July 16
  - 147. Morris, Robert. to Governor Clinton. Concerning, the account against the State of New York for specific supplies & asking information of Gov. Clinton on various points. A, L. S. 5 p. folio, dated Philadelphia, 1781 July 25
  - 148. Morris, Robert, probably addressed to Gov. Clinton. Pointing out the erroneous ideas held by Americans as to the financial aid given by France, Spain & Holland to the United States. "Not a single State has acknowledged our Independence except France", 1781 October 19
  - 149. Clinton, George (Governor), copy of his letter to His Excellency, John Hanson Esq., President of Congress. Also Copy of Resolutions of the Senate & Assembly of the State of New York of the 21st November 1731. "They entertain very slender Hopes of the, 1781 November 24
  - 150. Morris, Robert (probably). Part of a letter, presumably sent by Morris either to the President of Congress or to the Governor of the State of New York, explaining at length his scheme for funding the national debt D. 24 p. quarto, dated Office of Fin, 1782 July 29
  - 151. L'Hommedieu, [DOUBT-], addressed to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. Refers to Yates' desire to obtain the position of Receiver of Taxes; mentions the acknowledgment of American Independence by Holland; the death of Col. Lawrence near, 1782 August 2
  - 152. Morris, Robert, to the commissioners for Settling Accounts of the States. Copy of Document made by William Barber & signed by Morris. The whole Is endorsed: - "Queres proposed by the Auditors appointed to settle the Acts. of the States of Maryland &, 1782 September 7
  - 153. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to James Duane Esq. Refers to his disappointment In not being appointed Receiver of Taxes. "I have had the Loan Office over three years without a Copper In pay". Draft of letter in Yates' autograph, 2 p. folio, dated Albany, 1782 September 7
  - 154. Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esq., Loan Officer for New York. "You will be pleased to transmit me all the Bills of Exchange now In your Office". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, 1782 September [DOUBT-]
  - 155. Duane, James, to Abraham Yates Junr. An Interesting, letter stating the Financier's (Morris') reasons for keeping the offices of Receiver and Loan Officer separate. Autograph letter signed 4 p. quarto, dated Philadelphia, 1782 September 15
  - 156. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to The Honble Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance. Refers to a Bill of Exchange which he will transmit with the Returns for the present month, Draft of letter. 1 p. quarto, dated Albany, 1782 September 21
  - 157. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to the Honble Robert Morris Esq., superintendent of Finance. Transmitting a Return for the Month of September and also a Bill of Exchange. Draft of letter. 1 p. small quarto, 1782 October 4
  - 158. Yates, Abraham, Junr.. draft of letter to the Hon'ble James Duane & Ezra L'Hommedieu. An interesting letter giving the substance of a conversation with Coll. Hamilton. "I told him I thought the Financier had too much Power already and that Congress h, 1782 October 19
  - 159. Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Junr. esquire, Contl, Loan Officer for the State of New York. "You will receive from the Treasurer of the United States a Discharge for the Bill of Exchange therein mentioned". L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finan, 1782 October 23
  - 160. McCall, J. (Secretary), to Abraham Yates Esqr., Commissioner of the C. L. 0. for the State of New York. Concerning a Bill of Exchange, L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, 1782 October 23
  - 161. L'Hommedieu, Ezra, addressed to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Albany, favoured by Colo. Gonsavolt (Gonsevoort), Referring to his demands for compensation for his services as Loan Officer. "The Prospects of Peace are not so favourable as th, 1782 October 28
  - 162. Loan Office. Endorsed: - "Return for October 1782 Copy", D. 2 p. quarto
  - 163. Appleton, Nathaniel, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Commisr. of Loans N. York, Albany. "My case is not in all respects similar to yours, but I am equally excluded from receiving the Continental Taxes, Mr. Morris apologized for this". A, L. S., 1782 November 1
  - 164. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter to the Honbl. Robert Morris Esq., Superintendent of Finance, Philadelphia. "I am exposed to Inconveniences by having devoted three whole Years to Service of the public for which I have not hitherto with repeated, 1782 November 4
  - 165. Morris, Robert, to Abraham Yates Esqr., Loan Officer of the State of New York at Albany. "As to the request you make of Money I am very sorry to say that it is not in my Power to comply with it". L. S. 2 p. quarto, dated Office of Finance, 1782 November 29
  - 166. Petry, William; Frank, John; Fox. Friedenrich, Their appraisal of certain lands forfeited by John Tompson. Endorsed: - "The within, supposed to have been sold by Gen. Gansevoort & Jeremiah Van Rensselaer". D. S., 1 p. quarto, dated Johnstown, 1785 February 10
  - 167. Howell, David (Judge), addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany, "The period will doubtless arrive when the Liberties of this country will fall a sacrifice, but I hope in God that It Is not nigh. I hope the Rough Hewer will continue, 1785 July 12
  - 168. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Judge David Howell. Refers to the pamphlets of Dr. Price & the Abbe De Mably & the five points discussed in them, relative to the dangers threatening the Government. draft of letter in Yates' autograph, 2 p. quarto, dated Al, 1785 August 28
  - 169. Gensevoort, Leonard. Addressed to the newspaper, relative to the superior claims of Abraham Ten Broeck to receive the suffrages of his countrymen rather than Abraham Yates. D. 7 p. folio, signed "A Freeholder", 1786
  - 130. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. Referring to Bills of the New Emission, Loan Office accounts recently examined by Col. Barber and "Certificates and vouchers to the amount of about 50,000 dollars. now in his hand, 1786 January 25
  - 171. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing (probably), "I am making ready to Dine at the Gover's where I expect to see Coll. Moron and some others that probably will give me information of the Loan office". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated, 1786 February 1